Laptop insurance or laptop warranty
acts as an invisible shield for you.
You will now know why the end is important.  This is what we are going to
discuss today.   For
us it's not just a laptop.  This
is our studio.  This is our battle field.   This is
our work station.  Seriously speaking,
this is the engine of our dreams.  We buy all these
things with the thought [music] that I should get such a
laptop, such a machine which will help
me in moving forward today and tomorrow
[music].  But it
is also very important to take care of things here.   Just
like you take care of other equipment in your home
or take care of yourself, there is
a specific need with this laptop
which is very important and
many people forget it in the hurry.   Even
I used to forget.  When I faced this problem
personally, that is why I am
bringing it before you all.  Like one
mistake, one spill, coffee or tea, anything
[MUSIC] or one theft of any kind of
your laptop or anything and it's all
over.  Your data, your plan, the
money you had saved, whatever you had
planned for the future, all of it goes to
waste and your planning
stops at the zero stage.  Or
you have to replan.  Now, it is a
different matter for those who have immense wealth.  He will
buy a new one.  But what about those
who invested money wisely
and
bought a laptop for a specific need [music] and 99% of us are like that.  When you buy
any expensive thing,
emotions also get attached to it.  But
this is where insurance and warranty come into play.
Every company gives you warranty.
But what does insurance mean here
?  Insurance acts as an invisible shield
that protects your creative mission for the
future.
[MUSIC] Now what's the difference between a warranty and this
?  Understand that warranty is a mechanic.  A
mechanic in the market who fixes internal faults.
If there is any fault in your laptop.
Something
related to the motherboard, something related to the SSD [music]
, whatever it is.
But insurance is a bodyguard that
protects you from external attacks.  That is if your laptop gets damaged due to water
, theft or any other accidental
damage.  Ok?   The
warranty covers your manufacturing
defects and how issues.
Insurance covers accidental damage, depth
and loss related to any kind of laptops.   If you
take extended warranty, you have to
pay some extra money.  But there are
monthly and annual premiums
when you talk about insurance.
Duration: Normally you get warranty of one year to 3 years
and can extend it.
But insurance is flexible.   It is
monthly, yearly and renewable.
Normally it is seen for a maximum of 2 years.
Warranty varies from manufacturer to
manufacturer and brand specific,
but insurance can be taken according to third
party insurance and bundled plans.
What is coverage
brother?  Internal hardware failures due to
any defects [Music] SSD RAM
Motherboard Display whatever there is any
internal defect everything will be taken care of
by warranty but where accidental damage
protection comes in, here the
company charges you extra money,
that is exactly after charging you that money
some insurance company is
involved there which is giving you accidental damage
protection.  But only a few
brands have this.  Not everyone gives it.
Like HP has.  DEL used to give.  Now
very few brands are offering it exactly.
Lenovo offers it on some laptops.  Not everyone
gives.  This is where our insurance comes in.
We
can take insurance coverage where they do not provide it.  How?  [Music] Stay tuned
to the video.  I will tell you further.  There are just a few
parameters when you take warranty or
extended warranty directly
from the brand.  So the parts that are changed are
directly from the brand.  There is a chance
that it may become a little faster but it does
not happen in the case of many people.  But
whatever happens, the manufacturing brand
deals directly.  But when you
do it through third party insurance, it first
goes to the brand.  But if the brand
refuses for any reason [music] then
they can also make you use third party equipment or
components [music].
And normally, extended warranty is
preferred by home users and office users.
But for content creators
like me or gamers or heavy
data travellers who travel to different places, they
go for both of them.  Why?  Please wait.  Yes, the
claim process is different for both.  On
one hand, a little bit can be done
by calling the brand directly.  On the other hand,
you have to show documents.   For
example, if your laptop is stolen or
broken, you have to show the photo or [music]
copy of the FIR
to the insurance company.  So that you
can claim this thing.  So insurance actually
plays a very important role.  Regardless, if
you get Rickly from the brand, it's
great.  Even if you do not get it from the brand,
you can still get extra from outside.  Be it
accidental damage, liquid spills,
theft, even fire or natural disaster.
Everything can be covered if
you are wearing a seal.  But
what is inside this shield?  It is
your responsibility to read this.  It
is your responsibility to check.  If you ask us, we will be
able to tell you which plan you
can take.  But the responsibility for this is your
own.  Now look, different
plans are available.  In this the coverage also depends accordingly.
Normally it ranges from ₹500 to ₹3000.  Which is its average range.
Door step pickup is available.  Your
brand also guarantees authorized repairs.
Some companies like OneAssist and
claim process it for you by making you fill out a form.
So that you can easily get the claim [music].
But you have to keep one thing in
mind.  In this process, your
laptop is covered but your laptop
charger or battery cover, all this is not covered
and if you have to take insurance then
you have to keep in mind that you have purchased the laptop
[Music] If you are buying third party
insurance then you have to
purchase the insurance within 7 to 30 days, within 7 to 1 month.  Some companies
say with in seven days.  Some companies
also provide you insurance quickly based on the condition of your laptop.
Extended warranty and
insurance are two different things.  Always keep this thing in
mind.  Extended warranty
from the brand and the insurance which I
explain to you above.  [Music] If you still have any doubts, please
ask in the comments section.  You know
we reply to everyone.  So your
laptop is your partner.  For him,
getting a seal is an investment.  Because this is
also your investment.  Some
people invest in
becoming content creators.  Study is important for some people.
Someone is coding.
Someone is
sitting with his plans for the future.  Because no
one knows what will happen tomorrow.  That's why [music] a
sealed-in electronics
is especially important for the electronics
you devote maximum time to.
[Music] So whenever you take your laptop offline
or online.  There are no options you
can select [Music].  And yes, whether it is
extended warranty or insurance, it
is important for you to take both of them after checking them.  As
I said, if you take insurance,
whether it is accidental damage, liquid
spills, theft, electrical service
, problem due to electrical surge
or natural disaster, everything gets
covered as part of the insurance.  Now brother
[music] from whom should I take this insurance?  Because the
brand charges a lot of money in the name of extended warranty.  She
even gives it for a little less.  [MUSIC]
But who should I get insurance from?  I did
purchase the laptop online.  Brother,
from where should I get this insurance now?
Look, the brand gives you one year warranty on the laptop.
But many people
take extended warranty of 3 years.
Extra money ₹000 ₹000 based on laptop
price, he varies and takes it.
But now if we do not take this or
that thing is not available on that particular laptop, then
through which companies we
can avail all these features as part of
insurance in which accidental damage, spill,
water spill, theft, everything is covered.
So for that there are some companies
which you can select [music] in
which the top insurance providers are
like Ora Policy which gives you
Accidental Liquid Electrical and Fire
[music] between Rs 700 to Rs 2000.
You can fill the form online and if you want to
claim the damage directly, you
can take the photo of it online.
Bajaj also gives it to you.  These people
also include screen electrical mechanical faults and theft in this.
So you
can buy directly from Bajaj Ali or
you can take insurance from Bajaj Reliance.
Additionally, you can select different options in Paisa Bazaar which
covers Apple, HP, DEL, Lenovo and other brands.  Their
price also varies between ₹700 [music] to ₹2000.
Also, you get all the options in One Assist,
ICICI LBD, Tes Global Assoc and Bajaj
Finance SI SEED.
Rest, which one will be
best for you among all these, you will be able to know better by doing
research but if you
want to take my opinion then
ask me in the comment, tell me the price of your laptop,
when did you buy the laptop, what
problem are you facing, tell me we will try
to help you and give you a better solution, now
brother how to apply, I have
bought the laptop online from Flipkart, now
how do I apply, look friend, keep the invoice of the laptop
ready.  Ok?  Also
visit the insurance provider's site.
Enter the model serial number and purchase date and
choose premium.  You choose how long you want the warranty to be, one, two or three years.
Accordingly the premium will be mentioned.  You
can also pay monthly premium.  You
can also pay the annual premium together.  But it
is important to remember some things that if you want to
take insurance then you have to take it within 30 days and
for some companies
you have to take it within 60 days only.  There are no covers for the charger, battery, or
accessories that
you see with laptops.  And if
your laptop is stolen, or if it is damaged, then
in that case it is necessary for you to submit a copy of the FIR
[music].  If there is damage
, whether it is due to fire or water
, whatever it is, you have to upload photos for that.
And yes as I
said above extended warranty and insurance
both are totally different things.  I hope this gives
you some idea of ​​what to do
?  How to get insurance?  How to
get warranty?  Which company
gives warranty and which does not?  If she doesn't
give it then what should you do?  If you still have
any doubts after this then please I am there
to help you guys.  Please like and
subscribe to the video.  See you
in the next upcoming video or review of
some laptop.